Kabuto, I'll tell you
about this kid later...
(大蛇丸)カブト… この子のことは
あとで説明してあげるわ。
More importantly...
それより 後ろの子ネズミ３匹も
ここへ呼んだら どう？
Why don't you call over
the three little mice behind you?
《ヤマト : すべて
お見通しってわけか》
So he's seen through
everything, huh...?
《サクラ : 合図！》
There's the signal!
(カブト)また キミか。
You again, huh...?
(大蛇丸)フフ… いく度か 見た顔ね。
I've seen that face often...
九尾の子もいるみたいだし…
少し 遊んであげましょうかね。
And it looks like
the Nine-Tails kid is here, too...
Maybe I'll play with
you guys a little.
Let's see who's become stronger...
you or Sasuke-kun.
(大蛇丸)サスケ君と どっちが
強くなってるか 見てあげるわ。
Give Sasuke...
(ナルト)サスケを… 返せ!!
back...!
"Give him back" is not the correct
way of saying it, Naruto-kun...
返せは ないだろう？ ナルト君。
Your reasoning is off...
ずれてるよ それ。
(カブト)サスケ君は 望んで
我々のもとに来たんだ。
Sasuke-kun came to us
because he wanted to.
For a man, you're too obsessed...
about the past.
引きずりすぎだよ 男のくせに。
未練たらしいね。
You need to resign yourself.
Shut up, four-eyes!
(サクラ)黙れ メガネ!!
You don't even know
how Naruto feels...
そうやって 冷静になんでも…。
ナルトの気持も知らないくせに！
Stop acting so cold
about everything!
If you want to know about Sasuke-kun,
サスケ君のことが知りたいなら➡
try forcing it out of me...
力ずくで 私から
聞き出してみなさい。
If you can, that is...
できればだけど。
うおぉ～っ!!
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
The Nine-Tails Unleashed!!
Naruto...
What is this?!
《ナルト！ これって…》
《サイ : なんだ？ あれは…》
What is that?
I see...
((自来也 : そうか…。
やはり 出てきたか。
So it appeared just as I thought...
(カカシ)おそらく
あのチャクラの形状からして➡
Judging from the shape
of the Chakra,
the number of tails will probably
continue to grow... and eventually...
尾は どんどん増えていき
最終的には ９本になる。
there will be nine.
That sums it up.
そういうことだのう…。
(カカシ)自来也様は
いったい 何本目まで？
Jiraiya-sama, how many tails
have you seen?
わしは 今までに
二度 死にかけたことがある。
I've come close...
to dying twice...
The first time, I broke
six ribs and both arms,
(自来也)一度目は
アバラ６本と両の腕が骨折➡
and several of my
internal organs ruptured...
内臓破裂が数か所。
It was when I tried to peek into
the women's bath at a hot spring
(自来也)温泉で
女風呂を覗こうとして➡
and you pounded me good, Tsunade...
綱手 お前に
思いっきりやられたときだ。
The other time was...
そして もう一度が…。
during Naruto's training
ナルトとの修業中➡
when I saw the fourth tail
of the Nine-Tailed Chakra.
アイツの九尾チャクラの
４本目の尾を見たときだ。
His anger became the trigger
怒りが引き金となり➡
妖狐の尾が生え 増えていった。
and the number of Fox Spirit tails
he grew increased.
He maintained consciousness up
until the third Fox Spirit tail.
(自来也)その妖狐の尾が
３本目のときまでは➡
アイツも 意識を保っていたが…。
But by the fourth tail,
４本目で
ついに見境がなくなり➡
he had lost all rationality and was
controlled by destructive impulses.
破壊衝動に支配されていった。
(自来也)まるで
小さな九尾の妖狐だ。
He was just like a small version
of the Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit.
Even with the
Fourth's seal
四代目の封印式があるのに➡
そこまで…。
うむ。
it can go that far?
Yes.
I don't know the details,
but I can say this for certain:
詳しくは わからぬが
はっきり言えることは➡
四代目の封印術が
弱まりつつあるのではないか➡
The Fourth's Sealing Jutsu
might very well...
ということだのう。
be weakening.
The Fourth's Sealing Jutsu...?
(綱手)あの四代目の封印術が…。
そんなことが…。
I can't believe it...
There's more...
(自来也)それとだ。
It may appear that when Naruto
is in the Nine-Tails state,
ナルトは 九尾状態において➡
he's being protected by
the Nine-Tail's Cloak...
チャクラが かたどる 妖狐の衣に
守られているように見えるが➡
実際には
逆に 妖狐の衣によって➡
But in actuality, his body was
continuing to suffer damage
from the Nine Tail's Cloak itself.
体にダメージを受け続けていた。
After the fourth tail formed,
４本目の尾が出たとき➡
his body, wrapped in the
Fox Spirit's Cloak, grew bloodied,
妖狐の衣をまとったヤツの体は
血まみれ➡
and he thrashed about
despite suffering serious injuries.
重傷を負いながら 暴れていた。
After the Fox Spirit's Cloak
dissipated,
妖狐の衣が消えたとき➡
his wounded body
ナルトの傷ついた体は➡
was healed by the Nine-Tails' Chakra
inside his body.
体内の九尾チャクラで回復する。
But if he continues to get hurt
…が あんなスピードで負傷と超回復を
繰り返していたら➡
and then heal at that
speed over and over...
Naruto's body will break down
and his life span will shorten.
確実に ナルトの体は蝕まれ
寿命を縮めてしまう。
That's why we need you...
Yamato!
だからこそ お前が必要なのだ
ヤマト。
You, who has inherited the cells
of the First Hokage Lord.
(綱手)初代火影様の細胞を
受け継いだ お前がな。
Now you're the only one...
(自来也)今や 人柱力を
コントロールできる可能性があるのは➡
who can control
the Jinchuriki Host.
お前だけだ。
(自来也)幸いなことに
初代の首飾りは➡
Fortunately for us,
Naruto happens to be wearing
the First's necklace...
ちょうど
ナルトが かけとるからのう。
(自来也)頼んだぞ))
We're counting on you...
Naruto-kun... you've grown
considerably as a Jinchuriki Host.
ナルト君 人柱力として
かなり成長してるね。
《カブト : 九尾の力が
どんどん強くなってるな》
The power of the Nine-Tails
is rapidly getting stronger...
The striking feature of
the "Jinchuriki Host" is
((チヨ婆 : 人柱力は 尾獣と共鳴し➡
how it utilizes unbelievable power
by resonating with the "Tailed Beast".
(信じられぬ力を使えるのが
特徴じゃ…))
Naruto...
《ナルト！》
フッ…。
人柱力らしく
なっちゃってるわね。
You're starting to become more like
a Jinchuriki Host, aren't you...
ナルト君。
Naruto-kun?
《なるほどね…》
I get it...
それで キミが…
見張り役に 選ばれたのね。
So that's why you were chosen to
keep watch over him, huh?
私の実験も
少しは 役に立ったじゃない…。
So my experiment turned out
to be somewhat useful...
《実験？》
Experiment...?
木ノ葉には
もう少し感謝してもらいたいわ…。
The Leaf should be thanking me
a little more for this...
ねぇ…。
私のかわいい実験体さん。
Don't you agree...
my adorable little test subject...?
実験体？
この方 いったい何者です？
Test subject?
Who the hell is this person?
昔… 私がまだ
木ノ葉にいた頃の話よ…。
It happened...
a long time ago when I was
still in the Hidden Leaf Village...
すべての忍の中で
唯一 木遁忍術を使い➡
Only one among all Shinobi
could use the Wood Style Ninjutsu
さらに 尾獣を意のままに
操ることができた➡
and control Tailed Beasts at will.
初代火影の力が欲しくてね…。
I wanted the power of the First Hokage.
初代の屍から
その中の遺伝子情報を取り出し➡
As an experiment I once took some DNA
information from the remains of the First Hokage...
遺伝的要素を 60体の子供の細胞に
組み込む 人体実験を➡
and implanted genetic components
into the cells of sixty children.
したことがあったんだけど…
拒絶反応が ひどくってね。
But their bodies violently rejected it,
バタバタ 死んでいったわ。
and they died while
kicking and struggling...
そろそろ 見切りを
つけようと思っていた頃に➡
Around the time when
I was about to give up,
別の実験で 足がついて
木ノ葉を出ることになったの。
I ended up being tracked by
another one of my experiments
and had to leave the village...
実験施設は そのままにしてね。
leaving my laboratory just as it was.
全員 死んだと思ってたけど
まさか 生き残りがいたとはね…。
I thought all the test
subjects had died...
but I never thought one of them
would still be alive.
《そうか…》
I get it...
((四柱牢の術！))
Four-Pillar Prison Jutsu!
《サクラ : こ… これって
初代様だけの秘術…。
Th-This is... the secret Jutsu that only
First Lord could use.
木遁忍術！
The Wood Style Ninjutsu!
なんで
ヤマト隊長が木遁忍術を!?》
How come Captain Yamato can use
the Wood Style Ninjutsu?
《だから 初代様だけの木遁を…》
So that's why he can use
the Wood Style
that only First Lord
could use...
《そういうことか》
So that's the story...
なるほどね。
I see...
では かつての
研究の成果ともいえる サンプルが➡
So it looks like we'll now
be able to obtain
今ここで 手に入りそうですね。
a sample from a product
of old research.
そんなことより 今は…
私のサスケ君が➡
More important than that...
I'd like to test out how strong
my Sasuke-kun has become...
どれくらい強くなってるか…。
by having him
fight against Naruto.
ためしに 目の前のナルト君と
やらせてみたいわね。
テメエの…。
He doesn't...
テメエのもんじゃねえ…！
He doesn't belong to you...!
ふぅ…！ くっ！
うぅ…！
オレの前で… 自分のものみてぇに➡
Don't talk about Sasuke...
in front of me...
サスケの名を口にするんじゃねえ！
like he belongs to you!
くっ…！ あれは！
That's...
《なんなの!? あのチャクラ…》
What's... that Chakra?!
《くっ… 空気が痛い》
The air stings...
グルルルル…！
Interesting...
おもしろい…。
No doubt about it.
《間違いない。
妖狐の衣… ３本目まで…》
It's the Fox Spirit's Cloak...
Three tails have formed...
《あ… あれが 人柱力の力…。
Th-That's... the power of
the Jinchuriki Host...
肌で感じてわかる…。
I can feel it in my bones...
This...
これは…
こんな おぞましいチャクラ➡
This terrifying Chakra...
コントロールできるような質の
チャクラじゃない！》
is not the kind that
can be controlled!
This is... Uzumaki Naruto's...
《これが うずまき ナルト…》
《九尾の力か…》
the Nine-Tail's power, huh?
ぐおぉ～!!
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
It begins.
hajimare
A long, long story about you
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
"Tears", "tears".
namidatte namidatte
I want to shed them in happy times
ureshii toki ni nagashitai
So what if I want them to float in pretty puddles?
kirei na mizutamari ukabetai no wa nani
The southern sky,
minami no sora ni
It twinkles.
matataiteiru
From all of the stars meeting.
hoshi no kazu hodo no deai kara
Learning about love, receiving a map.
ai wo manandari chizu wo morattari
Are connected.
tsunagatteku
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
Someday a new page will turn.
itsuka mekuru peeji ni
I'm sure it'll be filled with lots of people
kitto takusan no hito ga afureru
It begins,
hajimare
A long, long story about you.
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
Next Episode
What power!
＜ヤマト : 大蛇丸の側近 薬師 カブト。
To think there'd be that much power just with Chakra...
その実像は 謎に包まれている＞
And on top of that, he rampages letting his emotions take over.
It's as if he's not seeing what's around him.
＜カブトは 桔梗峠の戦いの戦場にて
発見され➡
That power of his is a problem,
木ノ葉の医療部隊隊長に
養子として引き取られた。
but this difficult situation is a great opportunity for me.
ゆえに その詳しい出生を
知る者はいない＞
Failure will not be tolerated.
My true mission assigned to me by my Danzo-sama
＜木ノ葉では 平凡な下忍を装い
その力を隠し続け➡
is about to begin.
The Top-Secret
Mission Begins
実際の戦闘では
医療忍術のセンスとキレで➡
Next episode: "The Top-Secret Mission Begins"
綱手様をも窮地に追い詰めた。
Intelligence Report
by the ANBU Black Ops.
on Yakushi Kabuto.
もともと カブトは 暁のサソリが
大蛇丸に差し向けたスパイだった。
Yakushi Kabuto is
Orochimaru's close aide.
His true persona is
shrouded in mystery.
ところが 大蛇丸に共感し
自ら寝返ったというが➡
"FIRST MYSTERY: BIRTH"
Kabuto is an enemy survivor
of the Battle at Kikyo Pass.
カブト自身の目的は わかっていない。
今後も カブトの動向に注意を払い
調査を重ねる必要があるだろう＞
He was adopted by the captain
of the Leaf Village Medical Unit.
Hence, nobody knows
the specific details of his birth.
"SECOND MYSTERY: SKILL"
In the Leaf Village, he continued
to hide his true skill
by posing as an average Genin.
But in actual battle, his skill
and acuteness with Medical Ninjutsu
drove even Tsunade-sama
into a difficult situation.
"THIRD MYSTERY: GOAL"
Kabuto was originally a spy sent to
Orochimaru by the Akatsuki's Sasori.
However, he seemed to have
empathized with Orochimaru
and went to the other side on his own.
But his intentions are unknown.
We need to keep an eye on
what Kabuto does in the future.
And the investigation should be continued.
"INTELLIGENCE REPORT ON KABUTO YAKUSHI
CONTINUING"